# ASHOK C

## UI DEVELOPER | REACT DEVELOPER

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Having over **5 years of experience** In building web applications with a responsive layout using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap And various other libraries and frameworks. I have past 2 years of experience in **React.js** a popular Javascript library.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **UI** Developer

- Mar 2022 to Nov 2023

**Fusion Innovative Limited., Chennai** ( A unit of Hardee Software Solution PVT LTD ) - www.fusioninnovative.com

- Developing highly interactive single page applications and build the reusable components using React js, React Bootstrap, Material UI and various other libraries and frameworks.
- Solid understanding of async request handling, props, and hooks.
- Possess a keen eye for detail and have the ability to translate wireframes and design concepts into pixel-perfect creations.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness using media queries and flexbox/grid layouts.
- Managed codebase efficiently using Git and GitHub for version control.

## Web Developer

- Dec 2019 to Jan 2022

#### **Neowep Software Solution.**, Dharmapuri

- www.neowep.com

- Developing highly interactive front-end user interfaces for web applications with a responsive layout using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Js, Sass, Bootstrap and various other libraries and frameworks.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness using media queries and flexbox layouts.

## Web Developer

- Aug 2018 to Nov 2019

## RSN Infotech PVT LTD., Dharmapuri

- www.rsninfotech.com

Developing highly interactive front-end user interfaces for web applications with a responsive layout using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and various other libraries and frameworks.

## CONTACT

63

+91 87547 11743

 $\square$ 

ashokashok7117@gmail.com

Q

Kodambakkam, Chennai - 600024

mî

linkedin.com/in/ashokchinnaiyan



ashok-cp-02.github.io/portfolio/

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc. Computer Science** 

- 2015 to 2018

Periyar University College of Arts & Science, Pappireddipatti, Dharmapuri.

- 66 % of Marks.

**HSC** 

- 2015

Govt, Higher Secondary School, Menasi, Dharmapuri.

- 61.5 % of Marks.

**SSLC** 

- 2013

Govt, Higher Secondary School, Menasi, Dharmapuri.

- 60 % of Marks.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

HTML5

React.is

CSS3

Material UI

**Javascript** 

React Bootstrap

SASS

Redux

Bootstrap 5

Context API

**J**Ouery

**REST API** 

Onpage SEO

React Hooks

Responsive UI

**Typescript** 

XAAMP

BitBucket

Git

VS Code

#### PROJECT DETAILS

## Project 1:

#### Fusion Kitchen (Food Ordering Website) - www.fusionkitchen.co.uk

Technology: React Js, AXIOS, React Toastify, React Helmet, React Bootstrap, Material UI, Context API, HTML5, SASS.

#### **Description:**

- I have developed highly interactive single page applications and build the reusable components using React js, React Bootstrap, Material UI and various other libraries and frameworks.
- The listing page is equipped with a variety of filtering options and provides comprehensive restaurant details.
- A menu page assists users in selecting items according to their categories, and menu item's included availability, top recommendations, and customer favourites. It also supports a feature for displaying additional item options through a popup, and seamlessly integrates with an API for menu data retrieval and updates.
- I have developed highly interactive single page applications and build the reusable components using React js, React Bootstrap, Material UI and various other libraries and frameworks.
- User can track order and they can maintain their account (My Account).
- This website has the feature for a Dark and Light theme for all pages.

**Responsibility:** The project involves gathering requirements, developing a user interface, and integrating with APIs and monitoring and improving front end performance. .

#### **Project 2:**

#### Fusion Innovative - www.fusioninnovative.com

Technology: React JS, AXIOS, React Bootstrap, Material UI, HTML5, SASS, React Helmet.

#### **Description:**

- This application provides insights into the organization's history, career opportunities, and partner affiliations, offering a
  comprehensive view of its journey.
- The application offers users the ability to submit inquiries and career applications through integrated API functionality.
- The application features a tailored employee review section designed to meet specific organizational needs.

Responsibility: The project involves gathering requirements and developing a user interface.

# Project 3:

#### Fusion My Business - www.fusionmybusiness.com

Technology: React JS, AXIOS, React Toastify, React Helmet, React Bootstrap, Material UI, HTML5, SASS.

#### **Description:**

- The homepage of FMB (Fusion My Business) highlights product descriptions and key application features and benefits.
- This page incorporates an inquiry form with seamless API integration for submitting inquiries and receiving responses.

**Responsibility:** I have updating and creating new website pages AND integrates with POST method API Integration, and optimizing on-page SEO for enhanced web functionality and search engine visibility.

## CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITY

- I have Participated in a National Workshop on "ANGULAR JS" Organized by SACRED HEART College Thirupattur.
- I have Participated in a National Workshop on "NODE JS" Organized by SACRED HEART College Thirupattur.

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Father Name : Chinnaiyan P

Gender : Male

Language Known : Tamil and English.

Hobbies : Photography, Playing Shuttle Cock.

Permanent Address : 2/102, Menasi (PO), Pappireddipatti (TK), Dharmapuri (DT), 636904.

Residential Address : 23/7, Bagavan Flats, Rangaragapuram, Kodambakkam, Chennai, 600024.

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above mentioned particulars are true to the best of my knowledge. I assure that I will be sincere and work towards the success of the organization.

Thanking You,